Sangram Barge

sangrambarge098@gmail.com • 7030366582 • Pune India • LinkedIn • GitHub

About Me

Dedicated backend software engineer with 2+ years of experience in technologies like Java, SpringBoot, Hibernate, SQL, REST etc. Familiarity with agile terminologies. Worked on backend/middleware application improving response time of services and maintaining standard coding practices.

Work Experience

Medline Industries India Senior Associate Java Developer (Zendesk, Pricing)

July 2023 – Present Pune, India

- Pitched and and executed modernisation initiative
 - Transitioning services from monolithic architecture to micro-services architecture
 - Reducing response time of middleware services from 10+ seconds to 1-3 seconds
- Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams like API-gateway, network ops to ensure seamless integration and functionality with org and zendesk environment
- Played a crucial role in the pricing project by collaborating with the pricing development team on various Spring Boot micro-services, incorporating multiple Spring Batch implementations for efficient and reliable data processing
- Created a java utility for manual QA team to convert test case excel to Jira template
- Created a Java GraalVM utility for Zendesk admins to create user audit with pluggable configuration JSON saving hours of manual user audit check

Associate Java Developer (Zendesk)

November 2021 – July 2023

- Understood and implemented middleware java services for Zendesk application
- Contributed on a React and Spring Boot stack for an internal tool for onboarding new joiners in the org

Skills

• Skills: Java 8+, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Spring Batch, MySQL, Shell Scripting, React, Golang

Education

Sunbeam Institute (CDAC)

May 2020 - October 2020

Diploma in Advanced Computing

Pune

Government College of Engineering

Chandrapur

Instrumentation Engineering

Government Polytechnic

2015 - 2017

2017 - 2020

Diploma in Electronics and Telecommunication

Kolhapur